<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Luca Schiek</title>
    <link>/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Luca Schiek</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:42:51 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>/projects/aboutme/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:42:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/aboutme/</guid>
      <description>… where it all started
Dear Visitor,
my name is Luca Schiek and I am the creator of this page. I am 22 years old and was born in Krefeld, Germany. During my high school years at the Gymnasium am Moltkeplatz, I socially engaged in the student-run humanitarian initiative Moltke für Afrika e.V. and played competitive tennis @HTC Blau-Weiß Krefeld.
Motivation
 “Talent wins games, but teamwork and intelligence win championships” - Michael Jordan</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stock Returns</title>
      <link>/projects/stockreturns/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:26:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/stockreturns/</guid>
      <description>We will use the tidyquant package to download historical data of stock prices, calculate returns, and examine the distribution of returns.
The file nyse.csv contains 508 stocks listed on the NYSE, their ticker symbol, name, the IPO (Initial Public Offering) year, and the sector and industry the company is in.
nyse &amp;lt;- read_csv(here::here(&amp;quot;data&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;nyse.csv&amp;quot;)) First, we want to get have a look at the industries the companies are operating in. Therefore, we create bar plot that shows as how many companies are in each industry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Inverted Yield Curve</title>
      <link>/projects/yieldcurve/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 22:26:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/yieldcurve/</guid>
      <description>The inverted yield curve
Every so often, we hear warnings from commentators on the “inverted yield curve” and its predictive power with respect to recessions. An explainer what a inverted yield curve is can be found here. If you’d rather listen to something, here is a great podcast from NPR on yield curve indicators
In addition, many articles and commentators think that, e.g., Yield curve inversion is viewed as a harbinger of recession.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GDP Decomposition</title>
      <link>/projects/gdpdecomp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 21:28:43 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/gdpdecomp/</guid>
      <description>GDP components over time and among countries
At the risk of oversimplifying things, the main components of gross domestic product, GDP are Personal Consumption (C), business investment (I), government spending (G) and net exports. You can read more about GDP and the different approaches in calculating at the Wikipedia GDP page.
The GDP data we will look at is from the United Nations’ National Accounts Main Aggregates Database, which contains estimates of total GDP and its components for all countries from 1970 to today.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
